<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Dynamic Questions Guide</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on Dynamic Questions Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://canpake.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First post!</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/post/first-post-slug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/post/first-post-slug/</guid><description>This is my first post, how exciting!</description></item><item><title>Math Sample</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/post/math-sample/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/post/math-sample/</guid><description>&lt;p>KaTeX can be used to generate complex math formulas. It supports in-line math using the &lt;code>\\( ... \\)&lt;/code> delimiters, like this: \( E = mc^2 \). By default, it does &lt;em>not&lt;/em> support in-line delimiters &lt;code>$...$&lt;/code> because those occur too commonly in typical webpages. It supports displayed math using the &lt;code>$$&lt;/code> or &lt;code>\\[...\\]&lt;/code> delimiters, like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Formula 1:
&lt;span class="math">\(
\phi = \frac{(1+\sqrt{5})}{2} = 1.6180339887\cdots
\)&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Formula 2: (same formula, different delimiter)
\[
\phi = \frac{(1+\sqrt{5})}{2} = 1.6180339887\cdots
\]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additional details can be found on &lt;a href="https://github.com/Khan/KaTeX">GitHub&lt;/a> or on the &lt;a href="http://tiddlywiki.com/plugins/tiddlywiki/katex/">Wiki&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code Sample</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/post/code-sample/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/post/code-sample/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following are two code samples using syntax highlighting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1.1. What are Dynamic Questions?</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/dynamic-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/dynamic-questions/</guid><description>Dynamic questions are used when we have a good conceptual question that we&amp;rsquo;d like to ask repeatedly, with different valued constants each time the question is displayed. In these cases, code can be used to randomise certain parameters in the question, and then generate the corresponding question text, answers, and solutions.
An example of a dynamic question, viewed several times, is shown below:
Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 As you can see in the above images, the question changes each time the question is viewed, with different answers and solutions to go with the quadratic equation.</description></item><item><title>1.2. Using the QBM</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/using-the-qbm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/using-the-qbm/</guid><description>In our system, dynamic questions are created through directly writing PHP code in place of the usual text. To do so, after you&amp;rsquo;ve selected a round and level for your question, click on the &amp;ldquo;PHP&amp;rdquo; button in the editor:
The following text editor should appear, with automatically generated PHP tags (&amp;lt;?php and ?&amp;gt;) where PHP code should be written. Note that the closing ?&amp;gt; tag is important, and should not be removed to avoid any potential problems with how the code is run.</description></item><item><title>1.3. Formatting Text</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/formatting-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/formatting-text/</guid><description>When PHP calls echo on any string, it will ultimately be rendered as HTML. Because of this, text can be formatted by inserting the appropriate HTML tags into the strings.
You can try this yourself! As an example, enter the code below into the editor. You&amp;rsquo;ll see that the lines all apply formatting through the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;i&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;u&amp;gt; markup tags.
&amp;lt;?php echo &amp;#34;This text is normal. &amp;#34;; echo &amp;#34;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;This text is bolded!</description></item><item><title>1.4. Mathematical Expressions with AsciiMath</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/asciimath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/asciimath/</guid><description>We also have support for displaying mathematical expressions using the AsciiMath markup language - this was actually used in the example dynamic question you saw above.
Any bit of text can be rendered as an AsciiMath expression by simply encasing it in backticks (the ` character).
Note that this character is not the same as an apostrophe (')! You&amp;rsquo;d typically find this symbol on the top-left of a QWERTY keyboard.</description></item><item><title>1.5. Useful Editor Features</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/editor-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/1-intro/editor-features/</guid><description>The PHP editor is actually just a fancier version of the default &amp;lsquo;HTML Source&amp;rsquo; editor. Apart from syntax highlighting and autocompletion, there&amp;rsquo;s a few additional features of the editor that can allow you to write and edit code faster, including auto-indentation and a bunch of keyboard shortcuts.
Some main useful shortcuts will probably be these:
Windows Mac Action Alt-Shift-Up/Down Command-Option-Up/Down Copy (selected) lines up/down Alt-Up/Down Option-Up/Down Move (selected) lines up/down Tab Tab Indent (selection) Shift-Tab Shift-Tab Outdent (selection) Ctrl-Click Command-Click Add another cursor at clicked location Ctrl-Alt-Up/Down Ctrl-Option-Up/Down Add another cursor above/below the current cursor(s) Ctrl-F Command-F Find Ctrl-H Command-Option-F Replace A complete list of the shortcuts can be found here:</description></item><item><title>2.1. Common Issues with Dynamic Questions</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/2-design/common-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/2-design/common-issues/</guid><description>Listed below are some problems with dynamic questions that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and made myself before. They all stem from randomisation in code, but the nature of these issues can be rather different; some are directly involved with the code, while others are due to the design of the question and which values are randomised.
Either way, it can be helpful to take these considerations into account as you write your own code!</description></item><item><title>2.2. General Design Guidelines</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/2-design/guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/2-design/guidelines/</guid><description>Apart from the issues with code in a dynamic question, there also a few general things to consider when designing and writing a question. The guidelines below can be split into 3 main groups, and in summary they are to:
Consider Context: What the question is used for Consider Formatting: How the question is viewed Consider Wording + Detail: How the question will be understood While I&amp;rsquo;ll go into detail for each part, the key idea above all of this is to use common sense!</description></item><item><title>3.1.1 LibDQ</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/using-libraries/libdq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/using-libraries/libdq/</guid><description>The LibDQ library (as of the moment) has two main use cases to be aware of:
Rounding numbers to significant figures (sigfig) Displaying algebraic expressions and equations properly (gen_expr, and gen_eq) Below, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the relevant functions that provide the above functionality:
sigfig Example Usage Description gen_expr Example Usage Description gen_eq Example Usage Description sigfig /** * Returns a number rounded to a certain significant figure.</description></item><item><title>3.1.2. MathPHP</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/using-libraries/mathphp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/using-libraries/mathphp/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>3.2.1. Randomising Arithmetic</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/arithmetic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/arithmetic/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>3.2.2. Randomising Algebra + Graphs</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/algebra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/algebra/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>3.2.3. Randomising Geometry</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/geometry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/introducing-randomness/geometry/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>3.3.1. Rounding</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/formatting-values/rounding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/formatting-values/rounding/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>3.3.2. Algebraic Expressions</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/formatting-values/expressions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/3-coding-techniques/formatting-values/expressions/</guid><description> &amp;ndash; Incomplete Section</description></item><item><title>4.1. Example Question 1</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/examples/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/examples/1/</guid><description>Context: Volume of sphere given its SA This is an open-answer question that involves giving the surface area (SA) of a sphere, and asking for its volume.
The general mathematics behind this is fairly straightforward. We can use the two formulas for the volume and surface area of a sphere, given radius \(r\):
\[ \begin{aligned} SA &amp;= 4 \pi r^2 \\ V &amp;= {4 \pi r^3 \over 3} \\ \end{aligned} \]</description></item><item><title>4.2. Example Question 2</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/examples/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/examples/2/</guid><description>Context: Simplifying an inequality We'll be looking at an open-answer question that involves giving an inequality with a single variable, and asking for the simplified form of the inequality.
The inequality we'll give should be of one of the forms (where the boxes represent some random numbers):
\[ \begin{aligned} \Box (\Box x + \Box) &amp;\Box \end{aligned} \]
So an example question and solution might look something like this:
\[ \begin{aligned} \text{Question:} &amp; \\ &amp;&amp; 5(4x + 8) &amp;We can use algebra to figure out the answer in terms of the random values.</description></item><item><title>4.3.1. INFs and unrounded answers</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/1/</guid><description>Here's the example that was shown back in section 2.1:
In the above case, the formula for the volume of a sphere was directly used to calculate and display the answer. Let's look at the code involved:
$radius = mt_rand(5, 15); $answer = 4 / 3 * pi() * ($radius ** 3); While this seems fine at first, using pi() in calculations will give you messy numbers, and PHP will attempt to respond with as much precision as it can - giving us a number with 10 or so decimal places.</description></item><item><title>4.3.2. Floating-point errors</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/2/</guid><description>Floating-point errors, in summary, are basically where the computer makes tiny errors when doing arithmetic with decimals.
A rather specific example was given previously, but note that these issues can occur with simple decimal values as well. You can try this yourself:
Go to repl.it/languages/php_cli, and put this into the interpreter to see what you get:
&amp;lt;?php echo 0.1 + 0.2 - 0.3; ?&amp;gt; Rather than 0, we get a value that's very close to it - 5.</description></item><item><title>4.3.3. Weird random values</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/3/</guid><description> -- Incomplete Section
The aim in the above question is for students learn how to calculate distance when several speeds are given - but this does not apply if the speeds given are the same! --</description></item><item><title>4.3.4. Insufficient randomisation</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/4/</guid><description> -- Incomplete Section --
**Note:** As said in section 1, the order of solutions is randomised by default; this does not count as 'randomisation' in a dynamic question. As a rule of thumb, it would be good to have at least 20 possible variations of your question. More randomisation is better, but be careful of the next issue: --</description></item><item><title>4.3.5. Inconsistent difficulty</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/5/</guid><description> -- Incomplete Section --</description></item><item><title>4.3.6. (MCQs) Inappropriate choices</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/4-general-examples/solving-issues/6/</guid><description>-- Incomplete Section --
On the other hand, care is also needed when giving wrong answers that relate to the question - otherwise your wrong answers might be duplicates of each other, or even a correct solution themselves! This is an issue even if it rarely occurs, as thousands of students are going to be seeing these questions, and it's likely that they'll come across the problem at least once.</description></item><item><title>5.1. Example Question 3</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/5-advanced-examples/examples/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/5-advanced-examples/examples/1/</guid><description>Context: Real-World Graphs This is an open-answer question that will use graphs to show a constant rate of exchange between two items.
In this case, the structure of the question will be something like this:
Two farms, Farm A and Farm B, sell cherries at a constant rate per kilogram. The prices of these two suppliers are shown in the graph below.
[a graph of 2 straight lines, \(y = Ax\) (labelled 'farm A') and \(y = Bx\) (labelled 'farm B') for some values \(A B\)]</description></item><item><title>Contact Info</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/other/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/other/contact/</guid><description>If there&amp;rsquo;s stuff that doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite make sense or seems wrong, feel free to send me a message! While I&amp;rsquo;ll try to respond as soon as I can, do note that there are a lot of resources online that can help as well.
Here are a few ways to contact me:
Find me on the EV Slack! Send a DM, or to the channel #wmc-questions or #omc-questions. Email: jyim1120@gmail.</description></item></channel></rss>