<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1. Introduction on Dynamic Questions Guide</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/</link><description>Recent content in 1. Introduction on Dynamic Questions Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1.1. What are Dynamic Questions?</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/dynamic-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/dynamic-questions/</guid><description>Dynamic questions are used when we have a good conceptual question that we&amp;rsquo;d like to ask repeatedly, with different valued constants each time the question is displayed. In these cases, code can be used to randomise certain parameters in the question, and then generate the corresponding question text, answers, and solutions.
An example of a dynamic question, viewed several times, is shown below:
Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 As you can see in the above images, the question changes each time the question is viewed, with different answers and solutions to go with the quadratic equation.</description></item><item><title>1.2. Using the QBM</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/using-the-qbm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/using-the-qbm/</guid><description>In our system, dynamic questions are created through directly writing PHP code in place of the usual text. To do so, after you&amp;rsquo;ve selected a round and level for your question, click on the &amp;ldquo;PHP&amp;rdquo; button in the editor:
The following text editor should appear, with automatically generated PHP tags (&amp;lt;?php and ?&amp;gt;) where PHP code should be written. Note that the closing ?&amp;gt; tag is important, and should not be removed to avoid any potential problems with how the code is run.</description></item><item><title>1.3. Formatting Text</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/formatting-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/formatting-text/</guid><description>When PHP calls echo on any string, it will ultimately be rendered as HTML. Because of this, text can be formatted by inserting the appropriate HTML tags into the strings.
You can try this yourself! As an example, enter the code below into the editor. You&amp;rsquo;ll see that the lines all apply formatting through the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;i&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;u&amp;gt; markup tags.
&amp;lt;?php echo &amp;#34;This text is normal. &amp;#34;; echo &amp;#34;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;This text is bolded!</description></item><item><title>1.4. Mathematical Expressions with AsciiMath</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/asciimath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/asciimath/</guid><description>We also have support for displaying mathematical expressions using the AsciiMath markup language - this was used to display the quadratic equation in the example dynamic question displayed in Section 1.1.
Any bit of text can be rendered as an AsciiMath expression by simply encasing it in backticks (the ` character).
Note that this character (`) is not the same as an apostrophe (')! You&amp;rsquo;d typically find this symbol on the top-left of a QWERTY keyboard.</description></item><item><title>1.5. Useful Editor Features</title><link>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/editor-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://canpake.github.io/wiki/1-intro/editor-features/</guid><description>The PHP editor is actually just a fancier version of the default &amp;lsquo;HTML Source&amp;rsquo; editor. Apart from syntax highlighting and autocompletion, there&amp;rsquo;s a few additional features of the editor that can allow you to write and edit code faster, including auto-indentation and a bunch of keyboard shortcuts.
Some main useful shortcuts will probably be these:
Windows Mac Action Alt-Shift-Up/Down Command-Option-Up/Down Copy (selected) lines up/down Alt-Up/Down Option-Up/Down Move (selected) lines up/down Tab Tab Indent (selection) Shift-Tab Shift-Tab Outdent (selection) Ctrl-Click Command-Click Add another cursor at clicked location Ctrl-Alt-Up/Down Ctrl-Option-Up/Down Add another cursor above/below the current cursor(s) Ctrl-F Command-F Find Ctrl-H Command-Option-F Replace A complete list of the shortcuts can be found here: https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>